LEE LEMUS

Phone: (914) 826 3937 | Email: leelemus@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/leelemus Portfolio: https://leelemus.github.io/portfolio/ Address: 427 Pluto Street, Madison, WI 53718

Summary

Dynamic and resourceful Digital Expert with over 10 years of multi-industry and international experience in web development and digital marketing. Very experienced in implementing strategies and solutions that address client and business needs. An innate team player and relationship builder that enjoys working in the space where creative, digital, and development intersect.

Skills

Web Development / Design HTML, CSS and JS JSON, API GitHub CMS and DAM Administration Photoshop, Illustrator, GIMP Premier Pro Pro Tools Digital Marketing / Ecommerce
Social Media Management
Email Marketing
SEO and SEM
Campaign Automation
Google Analytics
Public Speaking
Relationship Building

Administrative / Other
Strategic Thinking
Team Management
Proactive Customer Service
Working w/ External & Internal Teams
International Sales & Marketing
Spanish Language Fluency

Work Experience

DIGITAL GROWTH MARKETING MANAGER - Bunker - Madison, WI - July 2018 - July 2019

- Implemented analytics infrastructure to measure traffic and up-funnel conversions.
- Implemented the use of landing page, email, and automation tools.
- Integrated all analytics and marketing tools to create an end to end MarTech stack.
- Worked with the engineering team to optimize SEO and conversion performance.
- Re-designed, implemented, and launched the company blog.
- Gave presentations about Bunker at various conferences.
- Created graphic and video content for marketing purposes.
- Worked with agencies to improve paid ad metrics.
- Tested and analyzed the performance of different digital ad and content channels.
- Help identify and pursue different customer segments.
- Interviewed various clients to gain further insight into their opinion of insurance products and feedback about our products and services.
- All activities above resulted in over 100% growth in traffic and conversions.

SALES AND MARKETING MANAGER - ARES Tool - Remote - December 2017 - July 2018

- Oversaw all e-commerce, digital marketing, and web development activities.
- Launched an e-commerce site, fully integrated to backend systems in under 30 days.
- Managed the advertising budget, maintaining a ROAS of 5:1.
- Developed brand identity and general brand style guidelines.
- Created and documented processes for order fulfillment and other e-commerce related tasks.
- Managed projects such as creating 20 product videos in one video session.

Managed a team consisting of a photographer, an operations specialist, and a copywriter.

DIGITAL ENGAGEMENT MARKETING MANAGER - Nasco - Ft. Atkinson, WI - November 2016 - December 2017

- Playing a vital role in shaping the branding of four different industry verticals via digital channels.
- Created and implemented Social Media infrastructure and content strategy, resulting in +200% growth in engagement, +40% growth in web traffic acquisition, and ROAS of 5 to 1.
- Helped initiate, monitor, and optimize Affiliate program with external partners, maintaining a conversion rate of +15%.
- Restructured and managed digital creative team for improved efficiency and quality of content.
- Create and oversee execution of company-wide seasonal promotions and web merchandising, resulting in +5% increase
 in conversions.
- Played key role in email marketing strategy implementation and transition to new ESP, helping increase open and click-through rate by +10%.
- Work with creative and photography teams to create imagery and video that is relevant and inspiring to target audiences.
- Conducted content audits for transition to new ecommerce web platform.
- Work with the Merchandising department in identifying featured products, trends, events, and stories.
- Maintain and monitor relationships with agencies running Affiliate, PPC, and Display advertising.
- Research and analyze trends, events, tools, and solutions that can positively impact each vertical of the business.
- Managing budget for maximum ROI.

MARKETING & COMMUNICATIONS MANAGER - Trek Bicycle Corporation - Waterloo, WI - July 2011 - March 2016

- Positioned Trek and Bontrager to be the number one high end cycling brand in Mexico.
- Consistently maintained web traffic growth of at least 25% year over year.
- Drove B2B online sales to be 55% of total yearly sales.
- Created social media page with reach and engagement growth of over 40% year over year.
- Increased email newsletter list by 30% with click through rates of at least 15% year over year.
- Created and led Ride Camp, a best practice event for all global markets.
- Was the voice and producer of all Spanish language content in western hemisphere markets.
- Initiated, nurtured, and leveraged relationships of all types to the brands' advantage.
- Attracted, sponsored, and worked with the best athletes and events in the market.
- Planned, controlled, and leveraged budget for maximum ROI.

DIGITAL MARKETING MANAGER - Tech Alliance - New York, NY - June 2009 - May 2011

- Boosted lead quantity and quality by 100% by revamping marketing message and strategy.
- Redesigned web site using HTML, CSS, JS, and PHP for optimal SEO, AdWord, and Analytics performance.
- Created engaging and purposeful content for marketing and sales.
- Maintained great relationships and provided great customer service to clients.

WEB DESIGN & PRODUCTION ASSOCIATE - WebMD - New York, NY - September 2008 - June 2009

- Produced standards compliant HTML and XML content.
- Enforced coding, styling, grammatical, data, and graphical standards.
- Increased article submission rate by 25%.

ONLINE MARKETING MANAGER - Brickhouse Security - New York, NY - September 2007 - September 2008

- Oversaw web and marketing projects to increase brand awareness and sales.
- Continually optimized performance of web and print advertising.
- Manage dynamic group of web, graphic, and marketing people.

WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER - Kuma Reality Games - New York, NY - March 2007 - September 2007

- Developed, designed and optimized user interface of games.
- Optimized web sites for SEO rankings.

Education

BACHELORS IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS - DeVry Institute of Technology - New York, NY - 1999 - 2002